Oleh Dudko

Front-End Developer

Toronto, ON | 416-500-0815 | o.dudko.ca@gmail.com | Linkedin | Github | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Front-End developer with 3 years of commercial industry experience of working for a large outsourcing company and proven ability to effectively collaborate with other developers. I have passion for coding so I am open to changing my tech stack, to receive new skills and get awesome experiences. Ready to apply my hardworking personality and talent to develop quality solutions and reach clients expectations.

SKILLS

Hard skills	
JavaScriptReact \ React HooksNextJSNode.js, Express	 JEST Redux / Redux TK CSS \ SCSS \ SASS Bootstrap \ MUI
REST API	HTML5
 MongoDB 	Git \ GitHub

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - Driver License Test App

08/2022 - 10/2022

- Worked on web development projects as assigned, taking a project from initial layout to a full responsive, functioning live site. Created functions for rendering, checking data, sending requests and business logic on the project. Performed cross-browser testing JEST and optimization.
- Developed SPA to improve the convenience speed of the application and allow users to update the quiz questions interface without reloading. Implemented Redux TK.Created business logic for data processing.
- Implemented the MUI and module styles to speed up development and create modern page design.
- Created REST API for app with Node.js and MongoDB. Developed a simple backend with Express.

Front End Developer - Halo Lab

11/2021 - 06/2022

- Independently wrote 3 projects using React/Redux and other libraries. Singlehandedly wrote an internal project using Sanity CMS + React, this allowed to reduce the project development time by more than 40%
- Participated in pair programming with 3 engineers, and reviewed team's code to provide additional perspective and catch previously missed errors. Worked in an agile environment with daily and weekly stand-ups and conducted 2 hours of sprint planning and sprint retrospectives per week.
- Independently designed and built my own SPA using CoinGecko API and React/Redux TK. Implemented a new API that helps create new services in the project. I implemented a Redux TK instead of Redux on a project, which helped to increase code readability and centralize state data.
- Changed the layout, imports types, and implemented a responsible design for a large project. This made it possible to use the application from tablets and 4k monitors and improved loading speed more than 15%.

Web Developer - BOO.UA

05/2020 - 11/2021

- Established user-friendly design, optimized pages with goods, cart page, check-out page, resulting in increased 20% user clicks and growth in 12% for adding products to cart. Added scripts of Google Analytics and other services to the project. Diagnosed and troubleshooting daily problems with a team.
- Developed new pages with new categories using React. Worked with multi pages in NodeJS for updating routing and generating new pages.support and maintenance of the website in high seasons.
- Provided technical support to client via phone, zoom, or other platforms. Agile methodology. Provided SEO practice while building new pages and categories. Advised on the administration of the site.

EDUCATION

2013 - 2019 Odesa, Ukraine